Hello everyone and we'll come to this class
on quantum mannings and computers.
Come rotation my name is mesh vary runny
and I'm am approve at the university of
Californians at Berkeley here. At birch Lee
we are very excited to be part of this.
Evolutionary inn education. Breathing, cutting,
edge courses; to any one in any part of the
word. So what? Is comptom communication?
Quantum communication. It's a very young feel.
Which is paste on? The disparity that
computer systems can be axed potentially
powerful. I'll see a lot more about. This is
in a subsequent video. but in this video I
want to talk about the format of the
course. The course is offered over eight
weeks followed by a final exam. The
material will be presented through a
series of short videos, which will be
augmented with inline quizzes to help you
reinforce your understanding of the
material. There will be seven problem
sets, each, each worth ten percent of the
score. And the problem sets will, will
have, mainly multiple choice, and
questions with numeric answers, which you
will turn in. To make sure that you
understand the material really well, we
will allow you to, make multiple attempts
at the problem sets. After your first
attempt, every subsequent attempt will be,
penalized ten%. If you want to understand
the material at greater depth, we'll also
include optional long questions. These you
do not have to turn in, but you're welcome
to discuss these with your fellow students
in, online forums which I'll talk about
later. The final 30 percent of your score
will be based on the final exam which is,
which you can think of as a particularly
long problem set. Okay, so what is the
required background for this course? So,
this course has been carefully designed to
make it accessible to students from a
multiple of backgrounds including Computer
Science, Physics, Chemistry, Mathematics,
etc. And so, we've tried to minimize the
number of requirements for this course.
So, in particular, I'll not assume any
prior knowledge of quantum mechanics. But
to take this course, you will need to have
a thoroug h understanding of basic linear
Algebra. What I mean by that is, simple
concepts such as vectors and matrices,
orthogonal bases, inner products, igon
values and igon vectors. To help you
review your knowledge of this material,
we, we will, we will include some sort of
supplementary material and, and perhaps a
video about this, about this subject. I'll
also assume very basic knowledge of
computer science. Things such as the big O
notation, or some elementary algorithms,
but particularly, how you analyze the
running time of algorithms by counting the
number of steps. There are few other
important issues we should go through.
This class has an honor code. This is the
same kind of honor code we have for our,
in class students here, in Berkeley. So,
you are allowed to, discuss the material
in this course, in fact, you're encouraged
to the discuss the material in this
course, with your fellow students. You can
even discuss the problem sets with your
fellow students, you know, to ask
clarifying questions, etc. But the answers
that you turn in have to be your own. In
addition, we'll request that you, not
distribute online the problem sets or any
of the answers, that we post. This is so
that, in subsequent offerings of these, of
this course, the students are allowed to
work independently on these questions.
I'll be posting course notes, every week.
You should think of this as a text book
for the class. This brings us to the
question of time management. So, you
should expect to spend anywhere from five
to twelve or more hours per week on this
course. Depending, of course, on the kind
of background you bring to this, to this
course, and also the depth to which you
want to understand the material. So, the
material is going to be formulated so
that, you can understand it, either at a
high level, or if you want to, you can use
this material as a spring book, to
understanding the various aspects of this
material at a greater depth. The course
notes will help you to do this, as well
the optional problem sets. There' s one
other important point, which is that
there's an online discussion forum for
this class, which will allow you to
interact with your fellow students. This
is a very important part of this class.
This will make it more fun for you, but
it'll also allow you to understand the
material at a greater depth. We also
encourage to form study groups, either
physically or through this online forum.
Okay, so, what will you learn in this
class. So, as I mentioned, one of the key
aspects of quantum computation is the
exponential power of quantum systems. So,
in this course you'll learn, what is the
source of this power? And how can you use
this source? How can you exploit this
power to design quantum algorithms? By the
end of this course, you'll, you'll
understand several iconic quantum
algorithms, including the quantum
algorithm for factoring integers
efficiently. You'll also learn what are
the limitations of the power of quantum
mechanics. In order to do all this, you
have to, have an, understanding of the
basic, of basic quantum mechanics, and so
another way to view this course is as a
simple and conceptional introduction to
the basic elements of quantum mechanics.
Okay. So, I look forward to having you in,
in this course.